{"test_questions": [[{"question": "According to principle of conservation of energy, the total momentum of a system of masses in any direction remains constant unless acted upon by an external force in that direction.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The friction experienced by a body, when in motion, is known as", "opta": "rolling friction", "optb": "dynamic friction", "optc": "limiting friction", "optd": "static friction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Two balls of equal mass and of perfectly elastic material are lying on the floor. One of the ball with velocity v is made to struck the second ball. Both the balls after impact will move with a velocity", "opta": "v", "optb": "v/2", "optc": "v/4", "optd": "v/8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The term 'force' may be defined as an agent which produces or tends to produce, destroys or tends to destroy motion.", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The coefficient of restitution for elastic bodies is one.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Coefficient of restitution for elastic bodies is 0 - 1.\nCoefficient of restitution for perfect elastic bodies is 1."}, {"question": "The velocity ratio in case of an inclined plane inclined at angle \u03b8 to the horizontal and weight being pulled up the inclined plane by vertical effort is", "opta": "sin \u03b8", "optb": "cos \u03b8", "optc": "tan \u03b8", "optd": "cosec \u03b8", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of projectile on a downward inclined plane is __________ the range on upward inclined plane for the same velocity of projection and angle of projection.", "opta": "less than", "optb": "more than", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The angle of inclination of a vehicle when moving along a circular path __________ upon its mass.", "opta": "depends", "optb": "does not depend", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A body of weight W is required to move up on rough inclined plane whose angle of inclination with the horizontal is \u03b1. The effort applied parallel to the plane is given by(where \u03bc = tan\u03c6 = Coefficient of friction between the plane and the body.)", "opta": "P = W tan\u03b1", "optb": "P = W tan(\u03b1 + \u03c6)", "optc": "P = W (sin\u03b1 + \u03bccos\u03b1)", "optd": "P = W (cos\u03b1 + \u03bcsin\u03b1)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the resultant of two equal forces has the same magnitude as either of the forces, then the angle between the two forces is", "opta": "30\u00b0", "optb": "60\u00b0", "optc": "90\u00b0", "optd": "120\u00b0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A smooth cylinder lying on its convex surface remains in __________ equilibrium.", "opta": "stable", "optb": "unstable", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Coefficient of friction is the ratio of the limiting friction to the normal reaction between the two bodies.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Moment of inertia of a circular section about an axis perpendicular to the section is", "opta": "\u03c0d3/16", "optb": "\u03c0d3/32", "optc": "\u03c0d4/32", "optd": "\u03c0d4/64", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time of flight (t) of a projectile on an upward inclined plane is(where u   =   Velocity of projection, \u03b1   =   Angle of projection, and \u03b2   =   Inclination of the plane with the horizontal.)", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit of angular acceleration is", "opta": "N-m", "optb": "m/s", "optc": "m/s2", "optd": "rad/s2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Moment of inertia of a triangular section of base (b) and height (h) about an axis passing through its C.G. and parallel to the base, is", "opta": "bh3/4", "optb": "bh3/8", "optc": "bh3/12", "optd": "bh3/36", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the masses of both the bodies, as shown in the below figure, are reduced to 50 percent, then tension in the string will be", "opta": "same", "optb": "half", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an equation of linear motion?(where, u and v = Initial and final velocity of the body, a = Acceleration of the body, and s = Displacement of the body in time t seconds.)", "opta": "v = u + a.t", "optb": "s = u.t + 1/2 a.t2", "optc": "v2 = u2+2a.s", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a number of forces are acting at a point, theirresultant will be inclined at an angle \u03b8 with the horizontal, such that", "opta": "tan \u03b8 = \u2211H/\u2211V", "optb": "tan \u03b8 = \u2211V/\u2211H", "optc": "tan \u03b8 = \u2211Vx\u2211H", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The above figure shows the two equal forces at right angles acting at a point. The value of force R acting along their bisector and in opposite direction is", "opta": "P/2", "optb": "2P", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The force required to move the body up the plane will be minimum if it makes an angle with the inclined plane __________ the angle of friction.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the shown figure, if the angle of inclination of the plane is increased, then acceleration of the system will", "opta": "increase", "optb": "decrease", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The total time taken by a projectile to reach maximum height and to return back to the ground, is known as time of flight.", "opta": "Yes", "optb": "No", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The frequency of oscillation of a torsional pendulum is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The range of a projectile is maximum, when the angle of projection is", "opta": "30\u00b0", "optb": "45\u00b0", "optc": "60\u00b0", "optd": "90\u00b0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mechanical advantage of a lifting machine is the ratio of", "opta": "distance moved by effort to the distance moved by load", "optb": "load lifted to the effort applied", "optc": "output to the input", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Static friction is always __________ dynamic friction.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A body will begin to move down an inclined plane if the angle of inclination of the plane is __________ the angle of friction.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a particle moves along a circular path with uniform velocity, there will be no tangential acceleration.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The bodies which rebound after impact are called", "opta": "inelastic bodies", "optb": "elastic bodies", "optc": "neither elastic nor inelastic bodies", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The maximum frictional force, which comes into play, when a body just begins to slide over the surface of the other body, is known as", "opta": "static friction", "optb": "dynamic friction", "optc": "limiting friction", "optd": "coefficient of friction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The centre of gravity of an equilateral triangle with each side a, is __________ from any of the three sides.", "opta": "3a/2", "optb": "23a", "optc": "a/23", "optd": "32a", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The distance, between the point of projection and the point where the projectile strikes the ground, is known as range.", "opta": "Correct", "optb": "Incorrect", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The algebraic sum of the resolved parts of a number of forces in a given direction is equal to the resolved part of their resultant in the same direction. This is known as", "opta": "principle of independence of forces", "optb": "principle of resolution of forces", "optc": "principle of transmissibility of forces", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The triangle law of forces states that if two forces acting simultaneously on a particle, be represented in magnitude and direction by the two sides of a triangle taken in order, then their resultant may be represented in magnitude and direction by the third side of a triangle, taken in opposite order.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The angle between two forces when the resultant is maximum and minimum respectively are", "opta": "0\u00b0 and 180\u00b0", "optb": "180\u00b0 and 0\u00b0", "optc": "90\u00b0 and 180\u00b0", "optd": "90\u00b0 and 0\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The path of the projectile is a parabola.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The equivalent length of a simple pendulum which gives the same frequency as compound pendulum is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A redundant frame is also called __________ frame.", "opta": "perfect", "optb": "imperfect", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mass moment of inertia of a uni form thin rod of mass M and length (l) about its mid-point and perpendicular to its length is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A resultant force is a single force which produces the same effect as produced by all the given forces acting on a body.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a rigid body is suspended vertically, and it oscillates with a small amplitude under the action of the force of gravity, the body is known as", "opta": "simple pendulum", "optb": "compound pendulum", "optc": "torsional pendulum", "optd": "second's pendulum", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Moment of inertia of a hollow circular section, as shown in the below figure about X-axis, is", "opta": "", "optb": "", "optc": "", "optd": "", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If two blocks of equal mass are attached to the two ends of a light string and one of the blocks is placed over a smooth horizontal plane while the other is hung freely after passing over a smooth pulley, then the two blocks will have some motion.", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During elastic impact, the relative velocity of the two bodies after impact is __________ the relative velocity of the two bodies before impact.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "equal and opposite to", "optc": "less than", "optd": "greater than", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Work done is said to be zero, when", "opta": "some force acts on a body, but displacement is zero", "optb": "no force acts on a body but some displacement takes place", "optc": "either (a) or (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The force which acts along the radius of a circle and directed away from the centre of the circle is called centrifugal force.", "opta": "Agree", "optb": "Disagree", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One watt is equal to", "opta": "0.1 joule/s", "optb": "1 joule/s", "optc": "10 joules/s", "optd": "100 joules/s", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "two like parallel forces are acting at a distance of 24 mm apart and their resultant is 20 N. It the line of action of the resultant is 6 mm from any given force, the two forces are", "opta": "15 N and 5 N", "optb": "20 N and 5 N", "optc": "15 N and 15 N", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If two bodies having masses m1 and m2 (m1>m2) have equal kinetic energies, the momentum of body having mass m1 is __________ the momentum of body having mass m2.", "opta": "equal to", "optb": "less than", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}